<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter [
<!ENTITY % common  SYSTEM "../../common/common.ent">
%common;
]>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="ch_overview">
        <title>Overview</title>
        <para>Cloud Networks enables you to create a virtual Layer 2 network, known as an isolated network, which gives you
                greater control and security when you deploy web applications. </para>
        <para>When you create a next generation Cloud Server, Cloud Networks enables you to attach one or more networks to
                your server. You can attach an isolated network that you have created or a Rackspace network. </para>
        <para>If you are using nova-network operations and you install the &virt_ext;, you can create a virtual interface to
                a specified Rackspace or isolated network and attach that network to an existing server instance. You can
                also list virtual interfaces for and delete virtual interfaces from a server instance. For information about
                the &virt_ext;, see <olink condition="cn" targetdoc="cn-devguide" targetptr="section_virt_ext">“Cloud
                        Networks Virtual Interface Extension”</olink><phrase condition="gs"/>
                <phrase condition="gs">
                        <link xlink:href="http://docs.rackspace.com/networks/api/v2/cn-devguide/content/section_virt_ext.html">
                Cloud Networks Virtual Interface Extension</link>
                        in the <citetitle>Cloud Networks Developer Guide</citetitle></phrase>.</para>
        <para>Cloud Networks enables you to attach one or more of the following networks to your server: <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold"><glossterm>PublicNet</glossterm></emphasis>. Provides access to
                                        the Internet, to Rackspace services (such as Cloud Monitoring, Managed Cloud Service
                                        Level support, RackConnect, and Cloud Backup), and to certain operating system
                                        updates. </para>
                                <para>When you list networks through Cloud Networks, PublicNet is labeled
                                                <literal>public</literal>. </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold"><glossterm>ServiceNet</glossterm></emphasis>. Provides access to
                                        Rackspace services such as Cloud Files, Cloud Databases, and Cloud Backup, and to
                                        certain packages and patches through an internal-only, multi-tenant network
                                        connection within each Rackspace data center. </para>
                                <para>When you list networks through Cloud Networks, ServiceNet is labeled
                                                <literal>private</literal>.</para>
                                <para>You can use ServiceNet for communications among web servers, application servers, and
                                        database servers without incurring bandwidth charges. However, without an isolated
                                        network, you must apply security rules to protect data integrity. When you add or
                                        remove a server, you must update the security rules on individual servers to permit
                                        or deny connections from newly added servers or removed servers. </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">Isolated</emphasis>. Enables you to deploy web applications on a
                                        virtual Layer 2 network that you create through Cloud Networks. An isolated network
                                        keeps your server separate from PublicNet, ServiceNet, or both. When you create a
                                        isolated network, it is associated with your tenant ID.</para>
                        </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
        <para>When you provision a new server, the networks that are attached to it depend on which of the following methods
                you use to provision it: <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">The Cloud Servers neutron API or nova-network API</emphasis>. You
                                        must specify the networks that you want to attach to your server. If you do not
                                        specify any networks, ServiceNet and PublicNet are attached by default. However, if
                                        you specify an isolated network, you must explicitly specify the UUIDs for PublicNet
                                        and ServiceNet to attach these networks to your server. The UUID for ServiceNet is
                                                <literal>11111111-1111-1111-1111-111111111111</literal>, and the UUID for
                                        PublicNet is <literal>00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000</literal>. </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">The nova <command>boot</command> command</emphasis>. You must
                                        specify the networks that you want to attach to your server. If you do not specify
                                        any networks, ServiceNet and PublicNet are attached by default. To attach to isolated
                                        networks that you have created, you must explicitly specify them in the command. If
                                        you do so, those networks, in addition to PublicNet and ServiceNet, are attached to
                                        your server.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">The Cloud Control Panel</emphasis>. PublicNet and ServiceNet are
                                        automatically attached, but you can disable these networks during the server creation
                                        process. You can also attach any isolated networks that you have created. </para>
                        </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
        <note>
                <para>You can explicitly opt out of attaching to the Rackspace networks, which introduces certain potential
                        complications. For more information, see <olink condition="cn" targetdoc="cn-devguide"
                                targetptr="networks">“Limitations of detaching from Rackspace networks”</olink>
                        <olink condition="gs" targetdoc="cn-gettingstarted" targetptr="networks">“Limitations of detaching
                                from Rackspace networks”</olink>.</para>
        </note>
        <para>You can use the Cloud Networks service to perform the following tasks: <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                                <para>List networks to which the specified tenant has access.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                                <para>Create isolated networks.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                                <para>Show details for isolated networks. </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                                <para>Delete an isolated network, but only if it is not associated with any server. </para>
                                <para>To detach a network from a server, you must use the &virt_ext; to delete the virtual
                                        interface for the network from the server. See <olink condition="cn"
                                                targetdoc="cn-devguide" targetptr="networks">“Limitations of detaching from
                                                Rackspace networks”</olink>
                                        <olink condition="gs" targetdoc="cn-gettingstarted" targetptr="networks">“Limitations
                                                of detaching from Rackspace networks”</olink>.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                                <para>Manage subnets.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                                <para>Manage ports.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                                <para>Manage Layer-3 routers.</para>
                        </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
        <para>To list the networks that are attached to servers, issue a Cloud Servers List Servers operation. For more
                information, see
                <link xlink:href="http://docs.rackspace.com/servers/api/v2/cs-devguide/content/List_Servers-d1e2078.html">List Servers</link>
                in the <citetitle>Cloud Servers Developer Guide</citetitle>.</para>
        <xi:include href="net_nova_v_neutron.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="net_limitations.xml"/>
</chapter>
