<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter [
<!ENTITY % common  SYSTEM "../../common/common.ent">
%common;
]>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" xml:id="ch_overview">
        <title>Overview</title>

        <para>The Rackspace Public Cloud enables you to attach one or more of the following networks to your server:</para>
        <variablelist>
                <varlistentry>
                        <term>Public (<emphasis role="bold"><glossterm>PublicNet</glossterm></emphasis>):</term>
                        <listitem>
                                <para>Rackspace PublicNet connects the cloud infrastructure components (like Servers, Cloud
                                        LoadBalancers, and Network appliances) to the internet. PublicNet is optimized for
                                        north-south traffic (traffic flowing to and from the internet). It follows a direct
                                        addressing model, so that all Public IP addresses are directly configured on the
                                        servers without being Network Address Translated (NAT'ed). PublicNet is dual-stacked
                                        for IPv4 and IPv6. When you create servers with PublicNet, your servers get an IPv4
                                        and an IPv6 address by default.</para>
                                <para>When you list networks, PublicNet is labeled <literal>public</literal>.</para>
                        </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                <varlistentry>
                        <term>Service (<emphasis role="bold"><glossterm>ServiceNet</glossterm></emphasis>)</term>
                        <listitem>
                                <para>ServiceNet is an internal, IPv4-only multi-tenant network within each Rackspace Cloud
                                        region that is optimized to carry east-west traffic. It provides servers access to
                                        regional services such as Cloud Files, Cloud Load Balancers, Cloud Databases, and
                                        Cloud Backup at no cost. ServiceNet is also required for Windows Cloud Server
                                        activation. We recommend that you connect servers to ServiceNet so that it can access
                                        the aforementioned services. The networks <literal>10.176.0.0/12</literal> and
                                                <literal>10.208.0.0/12</literal> are reserved for ServiceNet .</para>
                                <para>When you list networks, ServiceNet is labeled <literal>private</literal>.</para>
                        </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
                <varlistentry>
                        <term>Isolated Networks (Cloud Networks)</term>
                        <listitem>
                                <para>Isolated Networks are user-defined L2 networks that are fully isolated, single-tenant,
                                        and offer users a means to securely connect their application servers. They are
                                        provided at no charge. Isolated Networks can now be provisioned either as IPv4, IPv6
                                        or can be dual stacked (IPv4 and IPv6). Isolated Networks are recommended for all
                                        inter-server communication. Even though ServiceNet can also be used for server
                                        east-west (backend) connectivity, ServiceNet is not recommended for that purpose
                                        since , unlike Isolated Networks, ServiceNet is multi-tenant. Isolated Networks also
                                        includes full support for broadcasting and multicasting required for some clustering
                                        technologies. </para>
                        </listitem>
                </varlistentry>
        </variablelist>

        <para>When you provision a new server, the networks that are attached to it depend on which of the following methods
                you use to provision it: <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">The Cloud Servers neutron API</emphasis>: You must specify the
                                        networks that you want to attach to your server. The UUID for ServiceNet is
                                                <literal>11111111-1111-1111-1111-111111111111</literal>, and the UUID for
                                        PublicNet is <literal>00000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000000</literal>. </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">The nova <command>boot</command> command</emphasis>: You must
                                        specify the networks that you want to attach to your server. If you do not specify
                                        any networks, ServiceNet and PublicNet are attached by default. To attach to isolated
                                        networks that you have created, you must explicitly specify them in the command. If
                                        you do so, those networks, in addition to PublicNet and ServiceNet, are attached to
                                        your server.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                                <para><emphasis role="bold">The Cloud Control Panel</emphasis>: PublicNet and ServiceNet are
                                        automatically attached, but you can disable these networks during the server creation
                                        process. You can also attach any isolated networks that you have created. </para>
                        </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
        <note>
                <para>You can explicitly opt out of attaching to the Rackspace networks, which introduces certain potential
                        complications. For more information, see <olink condition="cn" targetdoc="cn-devguide"
                                targetptr="networks">“Limitations of detaching from Rackspace networks”</olink>
                        <olink condition="gs" targetdoc="cn-gettingstarted" targetptr="networks">“Limitations of detaching
                                from Rackspace networks”</olink>.</para>
        </note>
        <para>You can use the Cloud Networks service to perform the following tasks: <itemizedlist>
                        <listitem>
                                <para>List <glossterm baseform="network">networks</glossterm> to which the specified tenant
                                        has access.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                                <para>Create isolated networks.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                                <para>Show details for isolated networks. </para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                                <para>Delete an isolated network, but only if it is not associated with any server. </para>
                                <para>To detach a network from a server, you must use the &virt_ext; to delete the virtual
                                        interface for the network from the server. See <olink condition="cn"
                                                targetdoc="cn-devguide" targetptr="networks">“Limitations of detaching from
                                                Rackspace networks”</olink>
                                        <olink condition="gs" targetdoc="cn-gettingstarted" targetptr="networks">“Limitations
                                                of detaching from Rackspace networks”</olink>.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                                <para>Manage <glossterm baseform="subnet">subnets</glossterm>.</para>
                        </listitem>
                        <listitem>
                                <para>Manage <glossterm baseform="port">ports</glossterm>.</para>
                        </listitem>
                </itemizedlist></para>
<!--        <para>To list the networks that are attached to servers, issue a Cloud Servers List Servers operation. For more
                information, see
                <link xlink:href="http://docs.rackspace.com/servers/api/v2/cs-devguide/content/List_Servers-d1e2078.html">List Servers</link>
                in the <citetitle>Cloud Servers Developer Guide</citetitle>.</para>-->

        <xi:include href="net_nova_v_neutron.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="net_limitations.xml"/>
</chapter>
