<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter [
<!ENTITY % common  SYSTEM "../../common/common.ent">
%common;
]>
<chapter xml:id="how_examples_work" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0">
    <title>Learn how to use the examples in this guide</title>
    <para>For each exercise in this guide, you choose one of the following methods to make Cloud Networks API calls: <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">The neutron client</emphasis>. We recommend that you use the neutron client to
                    run simple commands that make neutron API calls. This open-source Python client runs on Linux or Mac OS X
                    systems and is easy to learn and use. You can specify a debug parameter on any neutron command to show
                    the underlying API request for the command. This is a good way to become familiar with API requests. </para>
                <!--<para>See <olink targetdoc="cn-gettingstarted" targetptr="novaclient">“How the nova Client
                    Works”</olink>.</para>-->
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">The
                        <link xlink:href="http://www.rackspace.com/knowledge_center/article/using-python-novaclient-with-the-rackspace-cloud">
                            nova client</link></emphasis>.
                    Use the nova client to run simple commands that make nova-network API calls. This open-source Python
                    client runs on Linux or Mac OS X systems and is easy to learn and use. You can specify a debug parameter
                    on any nova command to show the underlying API request for the command.</para>
                <para>See <olink targetdoc="cn-gettingstarted" targetptr="novaclient">“How the nova Client
                    Works”</olink>.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold"><link xlink:href="http://curl.haxx.se/">cURL</link> commands</emphasis>. If you
                    are familiar with or want to learn cURL commands, choose this method. With cURL, you send HTTP requests
                    with embedded API calls from the command line. The cURL examples in this guide show request and response
                    bodies that are in JSON and XML formats. See <olink targetdoc="cn-gettingstarted" targetptr="curl">“How
                        cURL Commands Work”</olink></para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>If you like, you can use cURL in one example and switch to the neutron client in the next example. If
        you choose to use a cURL command for any example, you must export the environment variables required to run the cURL
        examples. See <olink targetdoc="cn-gettingstarted" targetptr="export_env_vars">“(optional) Export Environment
            Variables to Run cURL Commands”</olink>.</para>
    <para>Each example, whether neutron client, nova client or cURL, points you to the next step in the process. </para>

    <xi:include href="net_how_client_works.xml"/>
    <xi:include href="net_how_curl_works.xml"/>
</chapter>
