<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter [
<!ENTITY % common  SYSTEM "../../common/common.ent">
%common;
]>
<chapter xml:id="security_groups" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
        xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" version="5.0" security="internal">
        <title>Use security groups to control traffic</title>
        <!--availwarn-->
        <important>
                <para>The Security Groups API is currently in Limited Availability. It is available only to Managed
                        Infrastructure customers and not to RackConnect or Managed Operations customers. To use this feature,
                        contact Rackspace Support.</para>
        </important>
        <para>A security group is a named container for security group rules, which provide Rackspace Public Cloud users the
                ability to specify the types of traffic that are allowed to pass through, to, and from ports
                (Public/ServiceNet) on a Cloud server instance. After an instance is active, you can assign one or more
                security groups to Neutron ports on that instance. You cannot apply security groups to a port at boot
                time.</para>
        <important>
                <para>There are no default security groups created for you in your Rackspace account. In order to use
                        security groups, you have to create them first and then apply them to Neutron ports that belong to
                        Cloud Server instances.</para>
        </important>
        <para>For more information about security groups and security group rules, see
                <link xlink:href="http://docs-beta.rackspace.com/drafts/catlook/webhelp/cn-devguide-external/content/conceptSecurityGroups.html">
                 <citetitle>draft version of Cloud Networks Developer Guide</citetitle></link>.</para>
        <para>The following flow chart shows the steps for creating, using, and modifying security groups and rules. Detailed
                steps are provided in this section. <figure>
                        <title>Steps to create, use, and modify security groups and rules</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                                <imageobject>
                                        <imagedata fileref="../figures/sg-neutron-api.png" contentwidth="3in"/>
                                </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                </figure>
        </para>
        <para>The sections are also organized by example type. To simplify your path through this chapter, decide whether you
                prefer neutron-client or cURL examples.</para>
        <!--<sidebar>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Next step:</emphasis>
                        <olink targetdoc="cn-gettingstarted" targetptr="sg_neutron_curl">“Use cURL”</olink></para>
        </sidebar>-->
        <sidebar>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Next step:</emphasis> Choose one of the following methods:<itemizedlist>
                                <listitem>
                                        <para><olink targetdoc="cn-gettingstarted" targetptr="sg_neutron_neutron">“Use
                                                        neutron client”</olink></para>
                                </listitem>
                                <listitem>
                                        <para><olink targetdoc="cn-gettingstarted" targetptr="sg_neutron_curl">“Use
                                                        cURL”</olink></para>
                                </listitem>
                        </itemizedlist></para>
        </sidebar>
        <xi:include href="sg_neutron_neutron.xml"/>
        <xi:include href="sg_neutron_curl.xml"/>
</chapter>
